PAUL SPENCER

Software Engineer

+31 6 46 395 141

• Amsterdam, The Netherlands

British and Irish (EU)

in linkedin.com/in/spencerpj

spencerpj.com

github.com/McFunshine

Summary

Software engineer with nearly three decades of delivering innovative solutions across fintech, energy, and govtech sectors. Completed a Master's in Software Engineering in 2022 while maintaining full-time employment. Currently architecting AI and emerging technology solutions while maintaining focus on practical business outcomes. Hardworking, adaptable and committed to continuous professional development.

Experience

Khonraad Software Engineering (GovTech services company)

Lead Emerging Technologies and AI Architect

Head of Innovation

Software Engineer

Apr 2019 – Aug 2019

Technologies: Kotlin, Java, C#, Azure, OpenAI, Kotlin Multiplatform, JetBrains MPS, Python

- Updated software to comply with new laws within core Java product development team
- Responsible for complete development lifecycle of the innovation projects, including:
 - A RAG chatbot providing guidance across the WvGGZ laws
 - A full-featured iOS and Android App using Kotlin Multiplatform with OpenAI integration
 - OCR integration solutions
 - Domain-specific language extension for Decision Engine using JetBrains MPS

Captain McFunshines Software Engineering (ZZP)

Freelance Software Engineer

Soest, The Netherlands Aug 2019 – Present

Technologies: Kotlin, Azure, AWS, OpenAI, Kotlin Multiplatform, Python

- Developed Podmorph, an AI-powered solution for podcast and radio professionals
- Integrated multiple AI services (Anthropic, Google AI, OpenAI, Groq, Replit, Fal AI) deployed on AWS and Azure
- Five-month .Net consultancy engagement with Baker Hughes

Baker Hughes (Oil Service Company)

Freelance Software Engineer
JewelEarth Platform Evangelist

 $Senior\ . Net\ Developer$

Delft, The Netherlands Aug 2019 – Dec 2019 Oct 2015 – Apr 2019 Jan 2014 – Oct 2015

Technologies: C#, SQL Server

- Served as principal technical contact for external developers building JewelSuite extensions
- Developed and delivered training to ecosystem partners worldwide
- Presented development tools at conferences and helped onboard partners
- Designed platform support procedures and set up support department
- Member of team that developed the SDK and API for the JewelSuite platform

Kempen & Co (Investment Bank) Senior .Net Developer

Developer

Technologies: C#, K2, SQL Server, VBA

Dec 2009 – Dec 2013 May 2007 – Dec 2009

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

- Delivered training on Entity Framework, Linq and Unit Testing/TDD

- Maintained and enhanced property securities indexing engine
- Developed application for maintaining and trading complex structured products

- Authored K2 Workflow (WWF) systems of business-critical processes

 ${\bf Unisys} \,\, ({\rm Technology} \,\, {\rm services} \,\, {\rm firm})$

Schiphol Rijk, The Netherlands

Developer

May 2001 – May 2007

Technologies: VBA, WebIntelligence, C#

- Responsible for reporting Accounts Receivables activity worldwide using WebIntelligence and Microsoft Office Automation
- Go-to person for fast turnaround ad hoc and recurring reports used for board-level decision making

 ${\bf ACT\ Financial\ Systems}\ ({\bf Software\ Company})$

London, UK

Developer

Nov 1999 - Apr 2001

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe, Visual Basic 6

- Supported and developed FISCAL, a bespoke multi-currency, multi-market settlement system for stockbrokers
- Used Universe Databasic (PICK) to solve business, procedural, functional and technical problems
- Investigated and remedied software bugs and data corruptions

HSBC Investment Bank (Investment Bank)

London, UK

Developer

Feb 1999 - Nov 1999

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe

- Developer for message processing, report writing, and screen handling programs

Lloyds Bank Stockbrokers (Stockbroker)

London, UK

Support / Business Analyst

May 1997 - Feb 1999

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe, VBA, Visual Basic 4

- Implemented, tested and supported various third-party and in-house projects
- Developed reports on the Fiscal Settlement System

Education

Universiteit van Amsterdam

Masters Software Engineering

Amsterdam, The Netherlands Graduated 2022

- Thesis: Projecting Rules: Improving Comprehension of Business Rules with Projectional Editing Making the Drools DSL Projectional with MPS
- Courses: Requirements Engineering; Sofware Specification, Verification and Testing; Software Construction;
 Software Process; Software Architecture; Software Evolution; DevOps and Cloud-based software
- Pre-Masters: Compilers; Functional Programming; Logic; Data Structures and Algorithms
- Languages Used: Haskell, C#, Java, Python

Note: Completed while maintaining full-time employment

Wolverhampton University BA European Business Administration Hogeschool Holland HEAO Joint European Business Administration

Wolverhampton, U.K. Graduated 1996 Amsterdam, The Netherlands Graduated 1996

Certifications

- 15 Microsoft Certifications including 5 MCPDs in Windows, Web and Azure
- Nederlands Als Een Tweede Taal (NT2) Niveau 2

Languages

- **English:** Mother Tongue
- Dutch: Fluent spoken, listening and reading, intermediate written

Additional Information

- Available from 1 August 2024
- Dutch Driving License (B)
- Open to relocation